Hello, everyone!
I'm Nadia.
I'm Nadia's friend, Jean.
I'm their cupid that'll
bring them together, Marie!
Marie!
But it's true!
Am I wrong?
In your eyes I see a bright future
Blue Water by Miho Morikawa
Lighting up everything
Thank you for always supporting
Nadia: The Secret of Blue Water.
Today we have an
exclusive video just for you.
We'll show you
the seven songs of Nadia
as well as a scene not yet broadcasted!
I think you're going to get to know
Nadia's cast and staff really well.
Have fun and watch until the end!
As it starts to play
It lets out a bit of happiness and courage!
In your eyes I see a bright future
Words are an eternal signal
Don't forget to try in mind
More than jewels
Love lights up everything
Nadia: The Secret of Blue Water
Hmmm?
Where are we?
- There are a lot of people.
- Where indeed?
Ah!
This is the chief director that created our
story and prepared each scene! Anno!
Ah, all our suffering was Anno's doing!
But look, he's smiling.
Nadia, don't be fooled by his smile.
He's the kind of person that
will finish you off with a smile.
Keep your guard up.
They go around and cut in twice.
It's just wrong.
I'm sorry.
No, it's fine.
Just where do director Anno's stories originate?
As one of his creations, I'm
especially interested in hearing it.
Alright! Let's take a peek
inside that brain of his!
The only way to move a
person's heart is through their soul.
It's a soul only they can posses.
You can't move people's
hearts with cheap tricks.
A person's soul, just like this airplane,
takes its weapons and aims for the heart.
We the staff of Nadia: The Secret of Blue Water
have spent a year and a half
putting our soul into production.
As long as you understand that, I'll be happy.
Let's Go Jean! by Noriko Hidaka
Jean! Jean! Jean!
My name is
Jean Rocque Raltique
I'm the number one
Scientist in the world
Unlimited possibilities
Hiding in your tiny chest
Don't throw your dreams away
Keep your spirits up
Let's go!
To the ocean!
To the sky!
A brighter tomorrow spells out our future!
Go, go, go, go, let's go!
Go, go, go, go, fight go!
The dawn of science is approaching!
Jean! Jean! Jean!
My name is
Jean Rocque Raltique
I'm a scientist of love and justice
A sharp intuition
Overflowing imagination
My theory is
Perfect!
Let's catch it!
That rainbow!
Our happiness!
The world is covered in a giant blanket of hope!
Go, go, go, go, guts go!
Go, go, go, go, dash go!
The dawn of science is approaching!
Let's go!
To the ocean!
To the sky!
Not by ourselves!
Everyone all together!
Go, go, go, go, let's go!
Go, go, go, go, fight go!
Humanity's awakening is approaching!
Jean! Jean! Jean!
I think I understand where Anno's
stories originate from a little better.
Yeah, he really admires science
and puts his imagination to the test!
But you know, drawing
and animating is hard work.
The three of us decided to
try our hand at animation.
Hello.
Excuse us.
Ah, it's so quiet.
Yeah.
This is where we can help make Nadia.
It's kind of...
It's a lot bigger than I thought.
Right? I didn't think it would be so spacious.
-Yeah
-Eh
I heard Anno is waking up from
a nap somewhere around here.
Here?
Really?
Does that mean there is a
resting room in this office?
Seems fun. Let's take a peek later.
Yeah, yeah.
The first step to animation is
you need to decide on a design.
For today, I've written that all here.
Read through it carefully and start working.
Ok.
Any questions?
Director.
Yes.
What is the most important
part of making animation?
Intuition.
Only your intuition?
Sense.
Only intuition and sense?
Also effort and willpower.
That makes sense!
It does.
I get it.
Let's try our best.
Please do.
Ok.
Doushite Sou Nano? by Yuko Mizutani
I guess you're al
fighting about messy, boring stuff
For being mature adults, you're all very rude
Why? How come it's like this?
All the glares and grumpy looks
Don't take it out on me, ok?
Let's go pick bouq
of red and white flowers instead!
Why? How come it's like this?
Come on, King, pay attention to my troubles!
1, 2, 3, I hate studying
A, B, C, I can't remember anything
1, 2, 3, I hate lectures too!
Why is it like this?
Why? How come it's like this?
Can we take a little break?
Snacks would be good.
I'm already tired.
Sorry. I haven't drawn much.
Why do you act like you're angry
It's all about your intuition.
That's what he said earlier.
Saying no to this and no to that
Why don't you pay more atten
to how blue the sky and sea are?
Why? How come it's like this?
Alright.
Perfect!
Ok, I'm not sure if it's perfect.
The more I look at it, the more I regret this.
Exhausted?
I'm glad we were able to finish by today.
I thought we would run over into tomorrow.
- Yoshino.
- For now...yes?
We have to redraw them.
Finished?
Somehow.
It's perfect!
We're all beat!
We had to redraw them.
That's tough.
This is really grueling work.
Yeah.
Ah, don't look!
To ho ho.
To ho ho, really explains my feelings right now.
- Oh My God
Shall we take a look?
Hmmm, alright.
Alright.
I decided what cut I wanted to draw.
Awesome!
Already?!
It's already over?
Wow, wow, wow!
1, 2, 3, I hate lectures too!
Why is it like this?
Why? How come it's like this?
"I'm going to give it my all
again this year! - Mizutani Yuko"
"Everyone should be upfront with their
feelings, just like Jean - Hidaka Noriko"
"Nadia is only just starting. Thank you
and keep watching! - Takamori Yoshiko
How did you like seeing it all together?
When I look at it like this, I'm glad I did it.
- Same, seeing it all strung together I'm glad I did it.
- I guess I've gotten better.
We only drew ten frames,
but I already felt burnt out after five.
I mean, you have to keep
drawing the same image.
Thank you and good job.
Thank you very much!
Your art sure was something.
I'm surprised that after all that hard work,
the final product was so short.
Yeah, I guess it's much better
if we stick to spreading love!
With that, we're going to show you
a recording at our recording studio.
Today we're actually
recording something!
Everyone is entering
one after another.
- Good morning.
Everyone is entering
one after another.
- Good morning.
Good morning.
Have A Nice Day.
Ok, take a look at this cut.
Where it says, I'm the heir
of the kingdom of Tartessos...
They record with all of these
voice actors together in one room.
Yeah, AR or after recording
is the technical term.
In other words, after the animation
is done the lines are recorded.
Abbreviated it ends up as AR.
When you say the kingdom, I
want you to stress the "king".
- Ok.
When you say the kingdom, I
want you to stress the "king".
- It's the last, so...
I think it was the first time I left early.
Really?
So you went first?
You actually came right at 10am.
You bet.
Got it.
Ok, let's start.
Things are finally starting.
Everyone looks like they're
on the edge of their seat.
Episode 35 - Secret of the Blue Water
Ai no Sannin Gumi by Kumiko Takizawa,
Henyu Horiguchi, Toshiharu Sakurai
Oh, are you in love with someone?
Oh, a love like fire!
Oh, leave your tears be
and set out on a journey
Come search for true love with us!
Even if it's to the ends of the universe
Don't worry.
I promised you.
I heard the sound of a bell...
This is bad, Jean! Run for it! Turn back!
- No, I can't let Nadia go alone!
Hey! Nadia!
Nadia!
You can't go in there!
What's wrong Nadia?!
Nadia!
Wait, Nadia!
Wow! Hey, hey! Nadia, let me try.
I can, can't I? Nadia!
Ok? Ok?
No!
All of the voice actors have
their own skills and techniques.
But, they sure have a strange
resemblance to their characters.
They say that when they're picking the voice actors
they choose people who are similar to the characters.
Hey, hey. I wonder how all
of them feel when recording?
I want to ask them!
I'm the voice of Electra, Inoue Kikuko.
Um...
I'm also the voice of the Nautilus's narration system.
As a character, I really feel that...
Hm....it's a waste to have her voiced by me.
I feel so fortunate to have this role.
The TV series will finish in March.
But I would be so excited to meet
all of you again in OVAs or movies.
Please continue to support us!
Hello.
I'm the voice of Captain Nemo, Otsuka Akio.
Captain Nemo, at his core,
is a uncommunicative person.
He's the kind of guy
that only talks if he has to.
It was a slightly challenging role to play, but I'm fond of it.
Thank you to all the fans.
Continue to stick with us.
I'm the voice of Ayerton, Tsujitani Koji.
Um... Ayerton's role was...
How could I say this? He is all over the place.
Um...you know...
One minute he'd be bragging about himself
and the next he'd say something of substance.
He'd pretends to be everyone's friend
and then turn around and betray them.
Basically, it's the role of a troublemaker.
Being the comedic unknown combo rather than,
say, the comedic love interest was a first for me.
Once I got into it, though, I realized
it was actually an entertaining role.
For a count such as myself, these trivial
matters are of little concern to me.
However, today, for  the sake of
everyone else, I shall participate.
I look forward to your continued patronage.
Good Luck, Everyone!
I'm Gargoyle's voice, Kiyokawa Motomu.
When I first got this role, I heard he was the villain.
Um...If this were a normal anime, the villain
would sound like a villain. I don't like that.
In the end, the villain dies not
knowing he was the villain.
If he does realize he's in
the wrong only at the end,
why not have him sound
like a good guy before?
No matter how bad the character is,
evil doesn't match my personality.
Whenever I have to voice a character like
that, I tend to give them a gentler voice.
It seems like Gargoyle reveals his face
in the end, so look forward to that.
Hello, everyone.
I'm the voice of Grandis Granva, Takizawa Kumiko.
It's already been 15 years since I
started working as a voice actress.
When I first started out, I was primarily
voicing little girls, around five years old.
Getting to voice a resolute gang leader character like Grandis has been incredibly fun.
I've been told our personalities are eerily
similar, but I didn't try to become her.
I worked very hard to make
her my very own character.
The staff didn't have many opportunities
to go out drinking, so it was little lonely.
I hope I can get together with
these members on the next project.
I don't know how many years later that
next project might be, but it would be nice.
I hope to keep taking on more roles,
so I look forward to your support.
See you.
I'm the voice of Hanson and King, Sakurai Toshiharu.
When you think about Hanson,
he looks like a bad guy.
Slowly but surely he became
a good kind of bad guy.
In a way, he warmed up to
Nadia and the rest of the group.
I feel like Hanson and I are similar.
It was a simple role to
understand and perform.
If you see me, I mean if you hear my
voice as Hanson or King, or any other role
I hope you'll store it in the back of your
head that it's Sakurai that did those voices.
Hello, I'm the voice of Sanson, Horiuchi Kenyu.
Sanson has a dirty mouth and is a bit uncivilized.
He's a multi-dimensional character
that is actually very kind.
He told Marie that story.
He cleansed himself by
telling that story to help Marie.
Now, the Horiuchi Kenyu you see in
front of you might look innocent,
but I have both uncivilized and kind sides to
me that I want to let out, just like Sanson.
At first, I wondered how I
would develop his character.
After a year passed, because of the importance of
the story and the bond with the other voice actors
I feel like I was able to
make the best Sanson.
To all the fans out there! I hope you become
a strong yet gentle person like Sanson.
Good luck, everyone!
Hello there, I play Marie. I'm Mizutani Yuko.
Hm, talking about my own character.
I'm often told I'm very mature, so I wasn't sure
about playing such a small child like Marie.
But that's actually not true at all.
I'm childish through and through.
When we first started, it was more of
a serious story with Nemo and Electra.
And in that serious story Marie just kind
of pops in and breaks all the tension.
When they went to South Island I was
worried she would break everyone.
It was kind of like,
"Oh, where did Marie go!"
I'm just saying, Anno really looks
like King when King's troubled.
Alrighty everyone! Nadia: The Secret of Blue Water
is getting a movie so please go and see it! Ok?
Excuse me.
I'm the voice of Jean, Hidaka Noriko.
Jean's character, Jean himself is a very honest.
But, he always thinks about Nadia
and helps her continue on her path.
He really is a good boy by trying to get her to go back
home, but compared to how I would handle the situation
I don't know if I could act so cold to her.
If it were actually me, I'd get mad.
I'd say, "Do whatever you want, you're so selfish!"
I've received lots of letters from fans
saying they admire Jean's kindness.
When I get letters from girls saying they want
a boyfriend like Jean, it makes me happy.
Anno is a big bully. You see,
Jean uses a lot of technical terms.
Anno kept saying I don't have to nerd out,
but that I still have to pack his lines full of emotion.
He intentionally kept telling me contradicting
things and writing the reading of super simple kanji.
Just looking at my script,
it felt like I was being bullied.
To make matters worse, during the
soundtrack recording I had difficulty with
he had complicated kanji that
I couldn't read for the life of me
and he wouldn't answer any of my
questions and I had to best guess it all.
I hold a strong grudge.
I'm going to try my best to
deal with Nadia's selfishness.
I'm sure everyone has their
own issues, so good luck!
Hello, everyone. I'm the voice
of Nadia, Takamori Yoshino.
Hmm, what can I say.
Nadia, as I'm sure you all know
is selfish, stubborn, and has a horrible
sense for understanding others.
She has difficulty meshing
well with others in the group.
I guess I could say she's poor
at managing her weaknesses.
But, you know, I've come to find
those parts of her truly adorable.
I was really worried about how
to play Nadia in the beginning.
But I came to understand what kind of girl Nadia
was, and by then I was already having a blast.
Even though we have to wake up really early,
I look forward to work every single morning.
I first worked with Shimizu, the sound director,
during my first lead role in Alpen Rose.
I gained a lot of popularity from that and got to
work again with him for Sonic Soldier Borgman.
Finally, we met again for Nadia.
He is such a friendly person.
I take a lot of creative
liberties while in the studio.
While he has faith in me, sometimes
when we go drinking, he'll say
"Yoshino, I don't know about that part
you did today" as a way of warning me.
I'm going to give it my all along with
Marie, Grandis, and the others.
Please cheer me on!
I'm the sound director Shimizu (Katsunori).
Probably, everyone's knowledge
about sound directors is fairly minimal.
It's a job that takes charge of all the
recording processes in the director's stead.
I have a lot of chances
to meet with the voice actors.
For this anime, for Nadia's cast,
we obviously had auditions.
For those auditions, we brought in all the
applicants and had them record right there.
Around 10 people, composed of musical and
agency producers also gathered to decide.
It was only 10 people, but everyone had their own
opinion about what was best, so it was still challenging.
For Nadia's cast, we ended up going with a lot of my
first choices, so it was easy to work with everyone.
Let's take a look at the other studio!
- Yeah!
- Ohhhh!
This studio is huge!
It really is!
This is the music recording studio.
It's where we recorded our
character songs and other music.
Ah, ah, ah, ah.
Oh, it's starting!
Ah, ah, ah. For the first...
Ah, ah. Too sharp?
Ah, ah, ah.
Ok, let's start recording.
Hajimete no Koi by Noriko Hidaka & Yoshino Takamori
For the first time in my life
I've noticed these feelings
You're always there, deep in my heart
Even if I know your teasing is a joke
I can't smile back, my heart is fluttering
So lonely and so painful
It makes me want to run away
I ignore you even though I'm happy
When you look at me
Why is it so blinding? (You)
Why am I so thrilled? (My heart)
Is this love?
Even the stars spark
outside my window make me sigh
So, why do these tears (In my heart)
Spill down my cheeks? (Hot)
Is this love?
If I close my eyes, I can see you smiling
And you don't even know how I feel
After it rains, the
is so blue it wraps me up
The Sun's gentle rays melt my heart away
Every morning I en
running into you on this road
It makes me pretty happy
So lonely and so painful
I can't really tell you how I feel
All you have to say is "good morning"
And my heart starts racing
But these feelings (Right now)
Are a secret (Shhh)
Is this love?
I'm happy just kno
I'll see you again tomorrow
Oh, these feelings (Mine)
Are so precious (Forever)
Yes, this is love
I want to always be able to watch over you
So, one day I'll tell you
I love you
But these feelings (Right now)
Are a secret (Shhh)
Is this love?
I'm happy just kno
I'll see you again tomorrow
Oh, these feelings (Mine)
Are so precious (Forever)
Yes, this is love
I want to always be able to watch over you
So, one day I'll tell you
I love you
Man, the pros know what they're doing.
Hearing it in the show is great and all, but
listening while they're recording is the best!
Hajimete no Koi was the first time for us to write
lyrics and for all three of us work together on lyrics.
Yeah that was hard work.
- It was!
- We were at that cafe...
-Really hard.
- That cafe...
How long were we working? Five hours?
- Five hours.
We were only able to get one
chorus done. One chorus, right?
We got about 1/3 of it finished.
- We got part way...
Making a song with three
people is surprisingly challenging.
- Yeah.
Making a song with three
people is surprisingly challenging.
I thought by combining our power
we would work three times as fast.
- I thought the same.
I thought by combining our power
we would work three times as fast.
Too bad it wasn't like that.
No triple speed.
It felt like that.
Once we put it all together and sang,
it turned into a wonderful song.
I thought so too. What about you?
It's silly little song but it's
the most popular song.
No way?!
I mean, it's such a cute song. It has such a heartwarming message.
Right? Looking at it from
an adult's perspective...
It's embarrassing.
I intended to completely turn
into Nadia for that song.
Nadia...
- I wonder what everyone else thought about it.
- Turn into...
Umi Yorimo Yasashiku by Yoshino Takamori
You know, somet
when I'm alone I feel faint of heart
I call out to the father and mother I don't know
I'll tell someone my secret
When I'm lonely at night, I look for the stars
But, I'll be much, much more gentle than the sea
I won't cry now, I'll keep on walking
The truth is, I'm al
pretending to be strong
As I hold on to this blue jewel at my chest
Someone please collect my tears
I'll search for love in all corners of the world
I'll become much, much bigger than the sea
I'll be sure to run far, far away
No matter how difficult
But, I'll be much, much more gentle than the sea.
I won't cry now, I'll keep on walking
I'll become much, much bigger than the sea
I'll be sure to run far, far away
That was an amazing song.
It was. It was!
It would be great if she always acted like that.
Yeah! Yeah!
Ahem.
By the way, the production staff put so much effort
into creating Nadia: Secret of the Blue Water.
Let's ask them about their
thought on the episodes.
Yeah!
Good job, everyone.
You've honored us with a great service.
I'm Mori (Takeshi). I worked on the
storyboards and as an episode director.
At first, Nadia felt like it
was just a crazy passion project.
But before I knew it, I was
completely drawn into the world.
By the time I realize it, I was working
solo as the episode director.
Other people ran away one after another.
Unable to get my revenge, I did my best to
stay on as the episode director until the end.
I think Nadia is a great anime, and I hope
everyone continues to enjoy it for years to come.
I'm the character designer, Sadamoto (Yoshiyuki).
I intended, yet struggled, on how to make
well received, easy to understand characters.
I'm one of the animation directors, Suzuki.
Watching episode one, I don't think anyone
imagined it would turn into such a hard SF story.
During the production of the first episode, Anno was
taken with Miyazaki Hayao's Kiki's Delivery Service.
I remember the first episode's
storyboards changed a lot.
The first episode was a real shocker.
I'm one of the mechanical, animation,
and episode directors, Masuo (Soichi).
You could say, this anime
shows off Anno's true passion.
He let us do what we wanted to do.
He was incredibly hospitable to a lot of us.
Artistically, it feels less like
a TV series and more like an OVA.
I think you'll have fun when you watch it.
I'm Maeda (Mahiro), credited as the setting director.
I also worked on storyboarding and other
jobs here and there. I did whatever I could.
It feels weird to call it harmonious...
I guess, for better or worse we
had a lot of fun making Nadia.
There were parts I regretted
and parts I enjoyed.
Because of that, I have a lot of
memories associated with Nadia.
I'll be happy if the parts I enjoyed while
in production translate to those watching.
When making Nadia, there was an
absolute rule we had to standby.
We couldn't lie to ourselves.
That was our one rule.
This was a show meant for children.
If we couldn't believe in ourselves,
how could they believe in us?
Additionally, there is always
another side to a situation.
This story features topics
like murder and war.
In respect to that, we don't talk negatively about
it, but we obviously don't talk positively about it.
We wanted to showcase all points of view.
All that's left is, well...
I started this project from the idea of wanting to
show the importance of people's encounters.
If the kids that watch this are glad they could
encounter an anime like this, I'd be overjoyed.
That's my wish.
What should I do a
this impatience in my heart
I've lost sight of my distant dream
I cry as I look up to the sky
Where our promise shines brightly
Try! Comforting words are like a breeze
That don't reach my heart
The anxieties I shoulder, grow
But I make my own decisions
So, I will probably be alright on my own
Even if I stumble, even if I get lost
There is always tomorrow